Alice Morey

Mobile: +(49) 157 5270 7455

Email address: info@alicemorey.com

Website/Online Portfolio: https://amoreywebdesign.com/

Profile

I am a London-born artist and web developer, currently based between Berlin and London. I recently completed a full-stack web development course with CareerFoundry (October 2024) and hold an MA in Fine Art from Chelsea College of Art (2020), Diploma in Art& Design from Camberwell College of Arts (2004), and a BA in Painting from University of Brighton (2008). Since moving to Berlin in 2009, I've exhibited regularly in London, Berlin, and internationally. With years of experience in customer service and market research, I'm a skilled listener and problem-solver. I also have a deep knowledge of the contemporary art scene and enjoy organising events, exhibitions, and performances, bringing artists together.

Work Experience

Job title (teacher/workshop leader/freelance)

Organisation Our Rights in Action/Landesjugendring Berlin e.V./ Obentrautstraße 57 | 10963 Berlin https://lirberlin.de/

Period October 2020- present

'Our Rights in Action': Empowerment of young refugees'- In the Landesjugendring project 'Our Rights in Action', refugee children and young people use creative methods to learn about children's rights and child protection. Their parents are also sensitised to the issues. Experienced speakers implement the programmes. 'Our Rights in Action' is funded by the state of Berlin.

- planning workshops and writing concepts
- buying materials and coordinating the workshops and activities
- working together with the children in groups and one to one
- evaluations of workshops

Working with an organisation that leads artistic and creative workshops in all the different refugee centres in Berlin.

Job title (contract)

Name of Company Klemm and Weber GmbH, Berlin, Germany

Start date 01/2014 - end date 01/2018

Bar keeper

- serving drinks to customers
- managing the evening, dealing with problems that arise and keeping an eye on co-workers

Job title (contract)

Name of Company Voxpark GmbH, Berlin, Germany

Start date 01/2014- end date 02/2015

Call centre agent for Sales team

- sales and marketing
- contacting clients by telephone and selling products.
- working on targets

Job title (part-time/freelance)

Name of Company Ipsos GmbH, Berlin, Germany

Start date 09/2010 – end date 05/2016

Working in an office environment, contacting businesses on the telephone

- market researcher, business to business calls and surveys
- customer queries

Job title (full-time)

Name of Company Itembase GmbH, Berlin, Germany

Start date 10/2013 - end date 01/2014

Working in a start-up company for an online shopping app for Ebay customers

- sales and service associate
- managing customer accounts for online app
- contacting clients and dealing with administrative tasks

Job title (part-time)

Name of Company ZMF e.V, Berlin, Germany

Start date 09/2010 - end date 09/2013

Events Manager at local music venue and Artist space

- coordinating events
- contacting Musicians and Artists
- assisting Artists and Musicians at the venue
- managing the events including the set up of light, sound and music
- updating all online promotion
- designing printed promotion

Voluntary Experience

Role Title Web design & developer

Name of organisation Kunstkombüse

Start date 07/2024 - end date 08/2024

Collaborative social project in Bad Segeberg

- In charge of online presence, updating website and social media
- Working closing with the team together with the programming of the project
- Attending regular meetings and discussions online, brainstorming ideas and output of the website, the online presence.
- using HTML, CSS to build a simple website of the project, problem solving the issues and giving it a quirky design.

Role Title Member of TopLab

Name of organisation TobLab, Schillerpalais, Berlin, Germany

Start date 06/2016 - end date 01/2018

Collaborative project space for art, science & technology, BioArt space

- In charge of online presence, updating website and social media
- Working closing together with the programming of the space, together with curators, scientists and artist collectives
- Attending regular meetings and discussions on relevant issues on art, technology, philosophy and science.

Role Title Member of Open Class

Name of organisation Open Class, UdK, Berlin, Germany

Start date 09/2017- end date 07/2018

Alternative gathering of artists, students and practitioners at the Art University in Berlin, organising workshops, exhibitions and discussions outside of the institution, a meeting point for learning and actively collaborating

- in charge of content of meetings
- attending regular meetings and discussions on relevant issues on art, technology, philosophy and science.

Practice Based Experience

Role Taken (Curator/Co-ordinator/Founder)

Name of Experience 'Globe Gallery', Heilstätte Grabowsee, Oranienburg, Germany

Start date 06/2013 - present

An alternative Art Gallery in the middle of a derelict hospital, Heilstätte Grabowsee, North of Berlin. We host an annual non-profit and alternative gathering with a full week of expressing your creativity through making art, inspiring workshops, readings, performances and social exchange. It's an open space for collaboration and we encourage contribution to the experience through your participation

- coordinating with all the artists, regular communication through email and meetings.
- Listening to all the artists ideas
- Organising the infrastructure of the project, food deliveries, cleaning, kitchen rotas, camping area, exhibition building, tools available.
- Helping the Artists with their individual projects and needs
- Hosting a festival at the end with music, performances and an exhibition.

Role Taken (Artist)

Name of Experience Conditioning Demands, Solo exhibition, MEWO Kunsthalle, Memmingen

Start date 06/2022- end date 09/2022

First institutional exhibition in Germany

- working closely alongside a curator and the team of the museum to produce an installation
- collaborated with various practitioners to make the objects, like a glass blower and a biologist
- regular meetings and brainstorms
- an artist talk at the museum with Q&A

Role Taken (Artist)

Name of Experience 'Shapes of Permanence', Solo exhibition, Porto, Portugal

Start date 06/2018- end date 09/2018

First solo exhibition in Portugal with commercial gallery, Lehmann + Silva, now represented as one of their five artists

- exhibition on two floors
- four large format paintings, two smaller format
- four hanging sculptures of found materials and fried plants
- installation with charcoal objects, tables, soil

Role Taken (Artist)

Name of Experience 'Performing states of hidden earth' Solo exhibition, Berlin, Germany Start date 03/2018 – end date 03/2018

Solo exhibition in Das Giftraum, a project space in a back room of a bar, spoken word performance on closing event

- large floor installation with found materials, broken clay objects and taxidermy pieces
- two large format paintings
- two smaller format
- hanging mobile structure

Role Taken (Artist)

Name of Experience 'Never, never ghosts' Duo Exhibition, London, UK

Start date 01/2018- end date 01/2018

Duo exhibition with Poet Ed Luker, piano performance and participatory installation on opening event

- large installation in centre of space
- two large format paintings, one smaller, with sound installation
- floor installation with found materials

Practice Based/Technical/Practical Skills

- Darkroom Processing and Printing
- Mounting frames, building stretchers and working with wood
- Hanging and handling artwork
- Able to use analogue and Digital SLR
- Printmaking
- Ceramic tools and materials
- Advanced knowledge of oil paints and pigments
- Photoshop CS6 (good)
- InDesign (good)
- Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint/ Advanced)
- Social Media Management (Facebook, Twitter, etc.)
- Microsoft / Mac proficiency
- English (native) / German (medium level)
- CSS (good)
- HTML (good)
- JavaScript (beginner)
- Angular/ React/ React Native (beginner)

Training/Coaching

Education

Career Foundry GmbH
Full-stack Web Development course
10/2023- 10/2024

University of the Arts London: Chelsea College of Art, UAL, London 10/2018 – 2020

MA Fine Art- Distinction

University of Brighton, Brighton, UK 09/2005 – 07/2008

University of the Arts London: Camberwell College of the Arts, London 09/2004 – 07/2005

Foundation Diploma in Art and Design – Merit

Elliott School, Putney, London A 'Level (2004)

Art – A

Theatre Studies- B

History-B

Burntwood School for Girls, London GCSE (2002)

Mathematics – B

English-B

Design-B

Science-B

Art- A*

Drama- A

Spanish- B

History- B

Artistic Merits / Exchange Programmes / Other Information

AIR, Artist in Residence, Beaulieu-zur-Meer, South France (March 2023)

Artist in Residence, BLANK100 x CRAIVERAL, Odemira, Portugal (Jan 2021)

Arist in Residence, Arnis, Germany (sept 2021)

Artist in Residence, Silkeborg Højskole, Denmark (2015)

Autocenter Summer Academy with Norbert Bisky, Berlin (2015)

Identity, Project exchange with Zwitschermaschine Gallery, Ostrava, Czech Republic (2014)

Artist in Residence Divo Institute, Kolin, Czech Republic (2011)

EXIT 09, Workshop with Jiri Kovanda, Kunsthaus Bethanien, Berlin (2010).

Publications

Todays best in contemporary Drawing, Vitamin D3, Phaidon (published 2021)- extract written by George Vasey Critic Pick, ArtForum written by Louisa Elderton 2022

Art Fairs

ARCO MADRID , Madrid, Lehmann + Silva 2022

Artissima, Turin, Lehmann + Silva 2022

Grants

2022 Stiftung Kunstfonds, NEUSTART KULTUR

2020 Kulturprojekten Berlin, Stipendien-Sonderprogramm 2020, Senatsverwaltung für Kultur und Europa, Berlin

2019 Erasmus + Stipendium, mobility traineeship, University of the Arts, London & Free University, Tbilisi, Georgia

2016 German-Czech Future fund, QM Schöneberger Norden and Tschechisches Zentrum Berlin for Exhibition: EKVALIZATOR

2.0 'In control, the uncontrollable'

2013 European Commission Youth in Action, 'Countdown Grabowsee' with Kids Globe e.V